<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>roasting on 1709 Brewing</title><link>https://beer.hubnut.ga/tags/roasting/</link><description>Recent content in roasting on 1709 Brewing</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</managingEditor><webMaster>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://beer.hubnut.ga/tags/roasting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fugly Blonde</title><link>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/fuggle-blonde/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</author><guid>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/fuggle-blonde/</guid><description>Here is a basic one that I brewed up today. The homebrew store was closed so I used what I had on hand. I had one pound of golden home roasted malt on hand (25 minutes at 300 deg) so I made this one up. I kept this simple because I wanted to use the pacman yeast that I harvested from Rogue bottles.
Pre Boil: 7 Gallons 10 Brix (76.5% efficiency)</description></item><item><title>Easy Common</title><link>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/easy-common/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</author><guid>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/easy-common/</guid><description>This is a non traditional Common. It does not hav e Norther Brewers hops, but it will hopefully taste good. I used my home made Dark Amber Malt for the first time! I also did a First Wort Hop, which I have never done before. We will see how it turns out.
UPDATE: This tastes AWESOME. It is really malty and the color is beautiful. Its a nice dark red. You can taste the home roasted malts, but thats because I roasted them the day before.</description></item><item><title>Dark Amber Malt</title><link>https://beer.hubnut.ga/techniques/dark-amber-malt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</author><guid>https://beer.hubnut.ga/techniques/dark-amber-malt/</guid><description>So last week I decided that I wanted to start home roasting my own malts. I found some awesome information here. I decided to make the dark amber malt.
I set up the oven at 375 and put 2 pounds of malt in the oven for 45 minutes. DAMN did it smell good. I am very excited for this one to be done.
I am very excited to try this one out in a brew.</description></item></channel></rss>