<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Techniques on 1709 Brewing</title><link>https://beer.hubnut.ga/techniques/</link><description>Recent content in Techniques on 1709 Brewing</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</managingEditor><webMaster>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://beer.hubnut.ga/techniques/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Canning Wort</title><link>https://beer.hubnut.ga/techniques/canning-wort/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</author><guid>https://beer.hubnut.ga/techniques/canning-wort/</guid><description>One of the most aggravating things about making a starter is that you have to boil the wort to sanitize. I would throw some DME, yeast nutrient and water into the clean flask. You then boil the wort in the flask and flash chill it. The whole process takes a while and if done one at a time is too much work. I recently bought a pressure cooker and it has made my life SO much easier.</description></item><item><title>Washing Yeast</title><link>https://beer.hubnut.ga/techniques/washing-yeast/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</author><guid>https://beer.hubnut.ga/techniques/washing-yeast/</guid><description>So washing yeast is easy cheap and efficient. The idea behind washing yeast is to wash it. Essentially you take the yeast cake from a previous beer and rinse the yeast and then store them in the fridge. It only take a few minutes and you can save a bunch of money on yeast by doing this. A single yeast cake can go a long way with washing yeast. The down side is that you need to create yeast starters.</description></item><item><title>Brutus 20 Runbook</title><link>https://beer.hubnut.ga/techniques/brutus-20-runbook/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</author><guid>https://beer.hubnut.ga/techniques/brutus-20-runbook/</guid><description>So I figured that I would get a runbook for the new Brutus 20 system. It is unedited and may change, but below is version 1.
Overview: Hose up the equipment for mashing Heat up the strike water while recirculating. Fill the Mash tun Dough in Mash Heat sparge water Recirculate all water raising overall temp to 170 Fill BK Boil Hop additions Hose up equipment for chilling Run boiling wort through the chiller to sanitize Turn off BK and turn on the cold water in plate chiller Rack the wort into fermenter Pitch yeast Cleanup Details: This is not so different from a normal brew day, with the exception that there is no pouring or lifting involved here.</description></item><item><title>Dark Amber Malt</title><link>https://beer.hubnut.ga/techniques/dark-amber-malt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</author><guid>https://beer.hubnut.ga/techniques/dark-amber-malt/</guid><description>So last week I decided that I wanted to start home roasting my own malts. I found some awesome information here. I decided to make the dark amber malt.
I set up the oven at 375 and put 2 pounds of malt in the oven for 45 minutes. DAMN did it smell good. I am very excited for this one to be done.
I am very excited to try this one out in a brew.</description></item></channel></rss>