<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Brutus 20 on 1709 Brewing</title><link>https://beer.hubnut.ga/tags/brutus-20/</link><description>Recent content in Brutus 20 on 1709 Brewing</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</managingEditor><webMaster>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://beer.hubnut.ga/tags/brutus-20/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Brutus 20 Runbook</title><link>https://beer.hubnut.ga/techniques/brutus-20-runbook/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</author><guid>https://beer.hubnut.ga/techniques/brutus-20-runbook/</guid><description>So I figured that I would get a runbook for the new Brutus 20 system. It is unedited and may change, but below is version 1.
Overview: Hose up the equipment for mashing Heat up the strike water while recirculating. Fill the Mash tun Dough in Mash Heat sparge water Recirculate all water raising overall temp to 170 Fill BK Boil Hop additions Hose up equipment for chilling Run boiling wort through the chiller to sanitize Turn off BK and turn on the cold water in plate chiller Rack the wort into fermenter Pitch yeast Cleanup Details: This is not so different from a normal brew day, with the exception that there is no pouring or lifting involved here.</description></item><item><title>Countertop Brutus 20</title><link>https://beer.hubnut.ga/projects/countertop-brutus-20/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</author><guid>https://beer.hubnut.ga/projects/countertop-brutus-20/</guid><description>So this is something that I have been working on for a few months. Ok&amp;hellip; in reality its been over a year. I thought this would be a great idea back in January 2010 and went out an bought all of the pieces. I ended up building my kettle and the chiller/pump toolbox and never actually making the controller. The design is mostly from jkarp on HBT. I customized this idea for my environment.</description></item></channel></rss>