<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>recipies on 1709 Brewing</title><link>https://beer.hubnut.ga/categories/recipies/</link><description>Recent content in recipies on 1709 Brewing</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</managingEditor><webMaster>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://beer.hubnut.ga/categories/recipies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Poblano Stout</title><link>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/poblano-stout/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</author><guid>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/poblano-stout/</guid><description>I am getting back into brewing and have made a few batches recently. I scalled down to 2.5 gallons and found that lasts about a month or more about 2 weeks. It is an ideal amount for Morgan and me as we will not get sick of any particular beer. I will however need to scale up my pipeline. Since it is winter and I can no longer enjoy the hop aroma and flavor, I have decided to start phasing into mouth feel beers for a while.</description></item><item><title>Rye Revenge</title><link>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/rye-revenge/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</author><guid>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/rye-revenge/</guid><description>It has been quite a while since I have been brewing. Now I have a different setup and live in a different part of the country. I just brewed the House Amber and that has been fermenting for a month. It is now time to start on the next beer. I have been in love with the Terrapin Rye, so I figured I would try a clone. There are many clone recipies out there, so I copied this fro many of those.</description></item><item><title>Fugly Blonde</title><link>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/fuggle-blonde/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</author><guid>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/fuggle-blonde/</guid><description>Here is a basic one that I brewed up today. The homebrew store was closed so I used what I had on hand. I had one pound of golden home roasted malt on hand (25 minutes at 300 deg) so I made this one up. I kept this simple because I wanted to use the pacman yeast that I harvested from Rogue bottles.
Pre Boil: 7 Gallons 10 Brix (76.5% efficiency)</description></item><item><title>Wheatever</title><link>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/wheatever/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</author><guid>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/wheatever/</guid><description>Simple recipe for a wheat that I made. It is fermenting now and started at 5 gallons 12 brix (12/10/11). Mashed at 152 deg.
UPDATE: I kegged it at 5.5 brix on 12/30/11. It is estery yet nice. It seems that it will be an easy wheat beer. (5.6% abv)
6 lbs White Wheat
4 lbs 2 Row
1 oz Hallertau @ 60 Min
Wyeast 1010 (washed)</description></item><item><title>Blonde Rye</title><link>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/blonde-rye/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</author><guid>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/blonde-rye/</guid><description>Here is a blonde rye I want to make. This is a try at a repro of my favorite rye I have ever made, hence the belgian yeast. I originally made one before loosing my recipes and I accidentally racked it onto a 550 yeast cake. It was ridiculously delicious.
  7 lb 2-row 2lb Rye Malt 1lb Flaked Corn (Maize) 1lb American White Wheat 1oz Cascade pellet 60 min 1oz Cascade pellet 10 min WLP550 Belgian Yeast</description></item><item><title>Cranberry Wheat</title><link>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/cranberry-wheat/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</author><guid>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/cranberry-wheat/</guid><description>So I give full credit of this recipe to my old roomante Andrew Wood. He has excellent ideas and was a great brewing partner. He came up with this recipe and it was light and delicious. So this is not technically a wheat beer, but whatever.
The secret to this recipe is the placement of the cranberries. Basically after the boil, you dump the boiling hot wort onto 4 lbs of frozen cranberries.</description></item><item><title>Fine Gael Irish Ale</title><link>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/fine-gael-irish-ale/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</author><guid>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/fine-gael-irish-ale/</guid><description>In 2009 I did my first all grain. I went out and bought a turkey fryer and a home depot 5 gallon cooler. I made what I thought was a SS braid ( turned out to be some sort of plastic) and started a mash with it. To my surprise, I was able to make it through the batch with out any trouble. I batch sparged, missed my numbers and ended up spilling some wort.</description></item><item><title>Red Rye</title><link>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/red-rye/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</author><guid>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/red-rye/</guid><description>So I want to brew up a red rye with the hops that I have. Here is what I am thinking.
UPDATE: I brewed this today (12/4/11) and it smells awesome. Mashed at 154 and ended up with 5.5 Gallons at 13 Brix.
7 lb. American 2-row 1 lb. American Munich 4 oz. CaraMunich 2 oz. Special B 1.5 lb. Flaked rye 1 lb. Rye malt 0.5 lb American crystal 120L</description></item><item><title>Brown Town</title><link>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/brown-town/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</author><guid>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/brown-town/</guid><description>I brewed this one up a few weeks back. I finally kegged it after a month in the fermenter. It is still carbonating, but I tasted it today and it is very nice. It has a nice nut flavor as you would expect with a Nut Brown. I will brew this again.
UPDATE: I tasted this again today and it is delicious. It is not as full bodied as I hoped, but I like it better than other Nut Browns that I have tasted.</description></item><item><title>Centennial Blonde</title><link>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/centennial-blonde/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</author><guid>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/centennial-blonde/</guid><description>Here is a basic blonde that I want to make. Its based on Centennial hops with a basic grain bill. It tastes like a hefe.
  7.00 lb Pale Malt (2 Row) US (2.0 SRM)
0.75 lb Cara-Pils/Dextrine (2.0 SRM)
0.50 lb Caramel/Crystal Malt - 10L (10.0 SRM)
0.50 lb Vienna Malt (3.5 SRM)
0.25 oz Centennial [9.50%] (55 min)
0.25 oz Centennial [9.50%] (35 min)
0.25 oz Cascade [7.</description></item><item><title>Easy Common</title><link>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/easy-common/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</author><guid>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/easy-common/</guid><description>This is a non traditional Common. It does not hav e Norther Brewers hops, but it will hopefully taste good. I used my home made Dark Amber Malt for the first time! I also did a First Wort Hop, which I have never done before. We will see how it turns out.
UPDATE: This tastes AWESOME. It is really malty and the color is beautiful. Its a nice dark red. You can taste the home roasted malts, but thats because I roasted them the day before.</description></item><item><title>House Amber</title><link>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/house-amber/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</author><guid>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/house-amber/</guid><description>This is my favorite recipe. I have not made this in a year or so, but I am going to get a nice pipeline of this going again and dedicate a tap for it. Maybe I will make a special tap handle for it. This normally comes out to 6.3% abv
House Amber American Amber Ale Type: All Grain Date: Batch Size (fermenter): 5.50 gal Boil Size: 7.04 gal Boil Time: 60 min Equipment: Pot and Cooler ( 5 Gal/40 L) - All Grain End of Boil Volume 6.</description></item><item><title>Red Headed Step Child</title><link>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/irish-read/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jarret.lavallee@gmail.com (jarret)</author><guid>https://beer.hubnut.ga/recipies/irish-read/</guid><description>This is an Irish Red (Hence the horrible pun). I brewed it as the first brew through my Brutus 20! It went very well except for overflowing my Mash Tun&amp;hellip; Oops. I hope it will be good.
Irish Red Type: All Grain Date: 10/29/2011 Batch Size (fermenter): 5.50 gal Boil Size: 7.04 gal Boil Time: 60 min Equipment: Pot and Cooler ( 5 Gal/40 L) - All Grain End of Boil Volume 6.</description></item></channel></rss>